<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Movements on SocioResources</title>
    <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/tags/social-movements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Movements on SocioResources</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>[CC-BY-SA](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en) Copyright © 2020 by Benjamin Geer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 04:13:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://socioresources.net/blog/tags/social-movements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Become an Obscure Public Sociologist</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/03/how-to-become-an-obscure-public-sociologist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 04:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/03/how-to-become-an-obscure-public-sociologist/</guid>
      <description>In the year 2000, I moved from New York to London. The protests against the World Trade Organization conference in Seattle had just taken place, and similar social movements were springing up around the world. I played a small role in this &amp;lsquo;alter-globalisation&amp;rsquo;1 movement, as one of the founders of a short-lived London branch of the international ATTAC network. Launched in France in 1998, ATTAC opposed neoliberal economics and advocated policies that aimed to limit the power of the global financial markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Translation of &#39;Autonomy and Symbolic Capital in an Academic Social Movement&#39;</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/03/arabic-translation-of-autonomy-and-symbolic-capital-in-an-academic-social-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 21:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/03/arabic-translation-of-autonomy-and-symbolic-capital-in-an-academic-social-movement/</guid>
      <description>Idafat: The Arab Journal of Sociology has just published an Arabic translation (open access) of my article, &amp;lsquo;Autonomy and Symbolic Capital in an Academic Social Movement: The March 9 Group in Egypt&amp;rsquo; . I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I was able to make this research accessible to more readers, especially readers in Egypt who have been directly affected by the events discussed in the article. The effort that I put into getting it published in Arabic will be rewarded if it contributes something to discussions about social movements in Egypt before and since the revolutionary uprising of 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Making of ‘Autonomy and Symbolic Capital in an Academic Social Movement’</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2014/05/the-making-of-autonomy-and-symbolic-capital-in-an-academic-social-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 21:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2014/05/the-making-of-autonomy-and-symbolic-capital-in-an-academic-social-movement/</guid>
      <description>The European Journal of Turkish Studies (EJTS) has just published my article &amp;lsquo;Autonomy and Symbolic Capital in an Academic Social Movement: The March 9 Group in Egypt&amp;rsquo; (open access), as part of a special issue on demobilization at universities in Turkey and in other countries.
What It&amp;rsquo;s About The March 9 Group for University Autonomy is a small group of Egyptian university professors who have campaigned, since 2003, against the regime&amp;rsquo;s interference in academic affairs and campus life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>