<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SocioResources</title>
    <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SocioResources</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>[CC-BY-SA](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en) Copyright © 2020 by Benjamin Geer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 08:59:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://socioresources.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Author</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/about-the-author/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 14:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/about-the-author/</guid>
      <description>In Brief My name is Benjamin Geer. I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer and researcher at the Data and Service Center for the Humanities at the University of Basel. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve served as Visiting Assistant Professor and Associate Director of the Middle East Studies Center at the American University in Cairo, and taught Arabic at the University of Tübingen. I did my PhD in Middle East Studies at the School of Oriental and African Studies (SOAS), University of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Scholars to Study Non-Scholarly Life</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2019/02/training-scholars-to-study-non-scholarly-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 08:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2019/02/training-scholars-to-study-non-scholarly-life/</guid>
      <description>Edward Said’s Orientalism pointed out the folly of assuming &amp;lsquo;that the swarming, unpredictable, and problematic mess in which human beings live can be understood on the basis of what books—texts—say,&amp;rsquo; but the field of Islamic Studies doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have paid much attention. Job descriptions emphasise knowledge of canonical texts, and published work, such as Shahab Ahmed&amp;rsquo;s What Is Islam? (2016), is often written as if you could understand, say, Sufism just by reading classical Sufi philosophy, without taking a close look at what Sufis actually do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surviving Sociology in Egypt and Elsewhere</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2017/02/surviving-sociology-in-egypt-and-elsewhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 18:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2017/02/surviving-sociology-in-egypt-and-elsewhere/</guid>
      <description>Mona Abaza interviews me on openDemocracy:
 There&amp;rsquo;s a school of thought that says it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether nations are real, because people behave as if they are. But false beliefs can have very destructive effects: think of witch trials, or the denial of climate science. Belief in nations is dangerous because, since they&amp;rsquo;re imaginary, you can say whatever you want about them and no one can prove you wrong&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Book: Ten Arab Filmmakers</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/04/new-book-ten-arab-filmmakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 21:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/04/new-book-ten-arab-filmmakers/</guid>
      <description>Ten Arab Filmmakers: Political Dissent and Social Critique is an edited volume about the films and careers of Arab directors whose films take a critical view of social realities. It includes a chapter by me (open access) on how the Egyptian filmmaker Yousry Nasrallah has succeeded in occupying a rather autonomous position in the cinematographic field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Become an Obscure Public Sociologist</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/03/how-to-become-an-obscure-public-sociologist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 04:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/03/how-to-become-an-obscure-public-sociologist/</guid>
      <description>In the year 2000, I moved from New York to London. The protests against the World Trade Organization conference in Seattle had just taken place, and similar social movements were springing up around the world. I played a small role in this &amp;lsquo;alter-globalisation&amp;rsquo;1 movement, as one of the founders of a short-lived London branch of the international ATTACnetwork. Launched in France in 1998, ATTAC opposed neoliberal economics and advocated policies that aimed to limit the power of the global financial markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Translation of &#39;Autonomy and Symbolic Capital in an Academic Social Movement&#39;</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/03/arabic-translation-of-autonomy-and-symbolic-capital-in-an-academic-social-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 21:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2015/03/arabic-translation-of-autonomy-and-symbolic-capital-in-an-academic-social-movement/</guid>
      <description>Idafat: The Arab Journal of Sociology has just published an Arabic translation (open access) of my article, &amp;lsquo;Autonomy and Symbolic Capital in an Academic Social Movement: The March 9 Group in Egypt&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I was able to make this research accessible to more readers, especially readers in Egypt who have been directly affected by the events discussed in the article. The effort that I put into getting it published in Arabic will be rewarded if it contributes something to discussions about social movements in Egypt before and since the revolutionary uprising of 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Making of ‘Autonomy and Symbolic Capital in an Academic Social Movement’</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2014/05/the-making-of-autonomy-and-symbolic-capital-in-an-academic-social-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 21:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2014/05/the-making-of-autonomy-and-symbolic-capital-in-an-academic-social-movement/</guid>
      <description>The European Journal of Turkish Studies (EJTS) has just published my article &amp;lsquo;Autonomy and Symbolic Capital in an Academic Social Movement: The March 9 Group in Egypt&amp;rsquo; (open access), as part of a special issue on demobilization at universities in Turkey and in other countries.
What It&amp;rsquo;s About The March 9 Group for University Autonomy is a small group of Egyptian university professors who have campaigned, since 2003, against the regime&amp;rsquo;s interference in academic affairs and campus life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sociology and the History of Islam</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2013/11/sociology-and-the-history-of-islam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 11:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2013/11/sociology-and-the-history-of-islam/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a video of a 40-minute introductory talk I gave on the Qur’an and the early history of Islam, on 30 January 2013 at the National University of Singapore. The talk was part of a lecture series called &amp;lsquo;Introduction to the Study of the Contemporary Middle East&amp;rsquo;, organised by the university&amp;rsquo;s Middle East Institute, where I was then a post-doc.
   I didn&amp;rsquo;t try to do anything more than summarise the current state of scholarship on the topic, including the main areas of disagreement among specialists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nationalist Tastes and Intellectual Struggles in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/2013/10/nationalist-tastes-and-intellectual-struggles-in-egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 13:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/2013/10/nationalist-tastes-and-intellectual-struggles-in-egypt/</guid>
      <description>This is a talk I gave at the annual meeting of the Middle East Studies Association in New Orleans on 12 October 2013, in the panel &amp;lsquo;The Politics of Taste in the Late Ottoman Empire and Egypt&amp;rsquo;. In under 15 minutes, it outlines the main argument of my PhD thesis and gives a few examples.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the abstract:
In the early 20th century, Egyptian effendi intellectuals used nationalism to introduce new tastes in literature, cinema, music, journalism, and other cultural practices into Egypt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Site</title>
      <link>https://socioresources.net/blog/about-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 19:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://socioresources.net/blog/about-this-site/</guid>
      <description>This blog focuses on the sociology of autonomy and the autonomy of sociology. There is currently one author, Benjamin Geer, who hopes that this will become a collective project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>